hello guys my name is robin tolentino
i'm a licensed insurance and investment
advisor and i've been in this business
for more than five years now and my
company deals with six of the biggest
companies in canada namely equitable
life rbc industrial alliance
manulife and canada protection plan
today for the purpose of uh
helping more of my clients
i will be explaining what a travel
insurance is okay and for the benefit of
more people
uh especially our kabbabayans i will be
speaking in filipino english or taglish
who have just purchased or signed up for
a travel insurance i will explain to you
guys
from the philippines or
alisporn in canada going to the
philippines i will just explain to you
the basics of a travel insurance policy
okay bob and the one i will be
explaining will be the one from manulife
here you go
so i will just turn the camera around
and then i will explain the the policy
all right all right so i will show you
paul
what a travel
insurance policy looks like
so this one is made
through manulife
so i already made some notes before i
pres i'm presenting this video or making
this video right now
so there will be two types of travel
insurance for manulife
there is a plan a and there's a plan b
i will explain it throughout the video
so
a for existed or pre-existing
condition
b is for
it already exists but it's stable so
a or plan a is for those who have a
condition let's say a hypertension or
some layman's terms of filipinos high
blood metastone blood pressure existing
napoleon divas or pre-existing condition
so that will not be covered to singapore
it's already pre-existing simply if
you're the insurance company
let's say or high blood pressure
i stable for a certain period of time
so plan b
okay
so plan a for existing
per pero if you're getting plan b they
will cover it for as long as the
existing condition for a new socket
diabetes hypertension
i stable
okay
so let's proceed to the next page
so there's a 10-day free look
so if you have this copy just print it
out if uh it was sent to you via email
just print it out there's a 10-day free
look which means
it says here if you notify us within 10
days of your purchase dates as indicated
on your confirmation that you are not
completely satisfied with your policy
we will provide a full refund so if you
don't like the policy
within 10 days they will provide or
manulife will provide a full refund
okay
and then
uh for as long as a subbing additional
refunds are only available
uh when manulife emerges uh receives
your request
for a refund before your departure date
yep
they will refund that boom
it is before you left the country uh
philippines to say philippines
[Music]
so
these are some
some points that you need to understand
as a trial dealer know your health
know your trip
know your policy this one and know your
rights
okay
and then uh you're also provided this
little
uh you can tap this output and then you
can put it in your pocket
or wallet and then yeah these is just
some um
this is a reminder
so your assistant center is open 24
hours a day
tapos
website
and
some
necessary information okay so an
important detonation
you have to call the assistance center
within 24 hours of hospitalization so
assistance center the number will be i
will give you the number later
or else
you will have to pay the 20
of your
medical expenses so you have to inform
them
the
assistance center immediately
[Music]
okay
so this is the next page i don't know if
you guys can see sorry but then of
course you have your own copies right so
this would be i would say page three
okay
important notice read your policy
carefully before you travel so
i mean i'm just doing this uh just to
help you out with the policy because
it's like 10 12 pages here so
just um
uh
a review or
a quick explanation of what the policy
is okay pero again you are fully
responsible for reading and you know
understanding the policy okay
so
if you have any questions you can inform
me or alexis who is my wife
na
could then like bent upon
okay
so read your policy carefully before you
travel travel insurance is designed to
cover losses arising from sudden and
unforeseeable circumstances so sudden
and unforeseeable circumstances
emergency
it is important that you read and
understand your policy before you travel
your policy may not provide coverage for
a medical condition and or symptoms that
existed prior to your trip go
does this is what i was saying a while
ago if you already have like say
hypertension or uncontrolled blood
pressure
that may not be covered
existing
responsibility now
so
it should be sudden and unforeseeable
circumstances
in the event of an accident injury
sickness uh your prior medical history
may be reviewed so
it's
uh high blood pressure
diabetes let's say and
you're trying to throw defraud the
company
a
they will do their research
your prior medical history may be
reviewed so they will do
a due diligence to check for example
a medical questionnaire they will find
out eventually from your doctor in the
philippines
blood pressure medications and
or let's say insulin so
during the medical questionnaire
on your application for the travel
insurance
be honest just be honest okay
uh and then nothing really super
important there but again i'm telling
you with
the policy yourself before i read the
policy
i'm just gonna highlight the the more
the most important um
uh
points here
identification of insurer so this policy
is underwritten by the manufacturers
life insurance company juniper you might
new life manufacturer's life insurance
okay
in the event of an emergency we're on
this part
numbers
of course as i said print this copy
or print this out from the email and
then bring it with you when you travel
because uh there's this phone number
here one eight seven seven eight seven
eight zero one four two if you are in
canada already or in the us
or anywhere anywhere else
uh plus one that's the
you know because the area code is five
one nine two five one five one six six
okay
so twenty four star hours a day each day
of the year boss we are so if you have
any questions you can call them okay
especially during an emergency
all right
and also there's an app
so you can download the app here for
www active care
active dash care dot ca slash
en slash travel aid slash okay
computers and you know
and then as i've said a while ago please
note that if you do not call the
assistant center
in an emergency and prior to treatment
you will have to pay 20 percent of the
eligible medical expenses we would
normally pay under this policy meaning
i would just give this a analogy
okay
and then the mechanic will say oh you
have to pay
twenty thousand pesos or one thousand
dollars
uh
in the end pina guam one thousand
dollars without contacting the
assistance center so what happens is
when they when they receive that invoice
they will
uh
not reimburse the entire thing yeah you
will have to pay the twenty percent
when you get sick
when you get into an emergency as much
as possible call the assistance center
within 24 hours
with the fees unless or the expenses
otherwise you will be charged the 20
so they will explain that to you if you
have questions you can call that number
that i just gave you okay but
and then
eligibility so who can apply pay down
visitors to canada just like the
philippines young canadians
are eligible for benefits
so canadians veteran persons who are in
age or
who are sorry in canada on a work visa
or parent or
[Music]
are not eligible okay
you are not eligible for coverage
you are traveling against the advice of
a physician
let's say your blood pressure i'll just
stick to the
heart condition okay now blood pressure
[Music]
or you have a kidney condition requiring
dialysis
weekly dialysis
you have used home oxygen during the 12
months so
uh you have been diagnosed with
alzheimer's disease or any other form of
dementia
in
[Music]
less than one month or 85 years old can
i begin i don't know however
or you reside in the nursing homes of
pilipinas or long-term care
center
if you require assistance with
activities
what else you need to know when applying
for coverage so coverage must not exceed
365 days one year
on full coverage but application for
insurance may be made before or after
you arrive in canada
[Music]
plan b
applicants 40 years of age or over so
comparing
or older
must complete the medical questionnaire
to use a plan b
waiting period okay
uh will apply except in the case of
injury okay so maybe it inferior
and then going to page i'd say page four
okay from the front
this is
uh page four
uh
[Music]
uh you may not be covered under more
than one plan during your trip so
um
you may not be covered
a 75 deductible applies to each claim
made under this policy
so it may 75 dollars unless
even deductible just to explain
[Music]
deductible deductible
one thousand
[Music]
economically buy them 5 000 and then 1
000 just a little company paypal you can
deduct the body
the deductible amount is the amount of
covered expenses that you are
responsible for paying per person so you
know
you are responsible for that deductible
okay
under plan a
uh under plan a no benefits are payable
for pre-existing
high
within the 180 days
prior to your effective date of
insurance so let's say alismosa
philippines by june 1st
so
180 days before june 1st and let's say
january 1st
so 180 days
uh within january 1st up to june first
within 180 days
meaning
uh
let's say controlled um
on blood pressure more with from january
first to let's say june first
so january to june first
[Music]
filipinas january first
january first the other year or let's
say january the second the other year
will empower 365 days
[Music]
apply december
two years ago
okay
you your health condition at impediment
within within a few months
more than one year back okay
family coverage uh
okay over uh the parents must be under
age 16
yeah so you must plan a
okay
again uh family coverage is available
under plan if you purchase then pay the
premium for primary coverage
the parents must be under the age of 60
and their unmarried dependent son or
daughter traveling with them must be
dependent
uh
30 days to 21 years old
considered the kids and then
environmental or physical disability
so
as
i said at the beginning print people on
policy okay
and then your coverage starts on the
later off
the effective date so
june
first
starts june 1st so june 1st
uh
position time and date you arrive in
canada
after the expiry date of an existing
manual life policy command existing
manual life policy
or after you leave home musa pilipinas
when coverage is purchased prior to
leaving home with an effective date
equal
to the dates
and time you are scheduled to arrive in
canada
coverage will also be provided with no
additional premium during your
uninterrupted flight directly to canada
okay so meaning
[Music]
uh prior to leaving home with an
effective date equal to the date and
time you are scheduled to arrive in
canada
magista
okay
with no additional premium okay
going the interrupted them flight
directly to canada
so an uninterrupted flight can include a
stop over provided you do not leave the
airport so
in japan
japan
[Music]
okay as long as you do not leave the
airport
then your coverage ends on the earliest
of the following so either tomorrow
each time you leave canada
when your policy expires as shown in
your confirmation so on a new
um
expiration date
i'll just move the camera here
and then when you become a resident of a
nursing home so looking
or no more than 365 days after your
effective date of insurance on lampasana
one year and call bridgemore
and then the first day you become
insured so in donating
let's say work permit
health insurance plan so you can really
go over
age okay
at no additional premium coverage is
included with the date and time you
arrive home following an uninterrupted
flight from canada directly home
um
[Music]
during your coverage period if you
return home so from example
but not
[Music]
but again as i've said
you have to inform the assistance center
okay
protect your your policy
insurance coverage
[Music]
coverage while traveling outside canada
excluding your country of origin
as long as your side trip originates so
for us
canada
[Music]
okay
and then put another automatic extension
of your coverage is provided beyond the
date
you were scheduled to return home as per
your confirmation if so automatic payday
might extend an email coverage again
called the assistance center
is delayed and prevents you from
traveling
on your expiry date
so they can cover you for another 72
hours or three days okay
or you or your travel companion
are hospitalized on your expiry
hospital
emergency department
so just make sure now
uh you will again
uh inform the assistance center
okay then there's this uh
paragraph here on how to extend your
coverage
i don't want to make this video too long
guys
okay
[Music]
if you are canceling your policy because
your application for a parent
and a grandparent visa was refused
to take care of your grandkids or your
kids
[Music]
approve for the visa so
and they will get you a full refund
assistance
[Music]
that's too late so you have to tell them
that
you have to call them
[Music]
this one is uh
for the parent and grandparent super
visa just so you know so he didn't
approve
application i own so
uh they will refund you okay
if you obtain canadian government health
insurance plan coverage
again
uh don't quote me but
i always uh refer i'm always referring
you to these numbers okay
okay
and then
if you hold the parent and grandparents
super visa and have purchased 365 days
of coverage and are requesting a partial
refund due to your yearly or your early
return to your home
grandparent visa pero
[Music]
okay but then
uh you have had no claim that has been
reported paid or denied
reported the claim or have a payable
claim for which the payment has not been
issued or the total amount of all
reported eligible claim expenses
or a claim has been paid no refund
okay so just call them up and you know
compare any questions about that
all right a written request to cancel
this policy must be received within 60
days
following the date you you return home
along with proof of your departure from
canada
so
within 60 days or two months
[Music]
uh
are called within 24 hours of
hospitalization i thought i mentioned
this a while ago
okay
if you do not contact the assistance
center before receiving medical
treatment you will have to pay 20 of the
medical expenses we would normally pay
under the insurance
[Music]
in any issues with any issues
call this number okay
uh the assistance center will verify and
explain your coverage okay so
they will assistance everything to you
okay
okay and you can email them here or mail
them
send them a letter
[Music]
okay your claim must be sent with us
with uh sent to us within 90 days so
within three months
bills and invoices commenting claims
what is cover demand under emergency
medical insurance at all we're talking
about emergency medical insurance
emergency
unforeseen
partner for medical attention uh related
to the medical attention you need if a
medical emergency begins unexpectedly
after
your effective date of insurance so like
starting insurance after no effective
date only start now
after your effective date of insurance
and when
these expenses are not covered by any
other benefit plans
[Music]
the maximum amount of payable is based
on the plan you have purchased
[Music]
you are responsible for paying per
person for emergency deductibles
[Music]
or grandparents insurance coverage okay
all medical procedures and our tests
including
or any surgery must be authorized by the
assistance center
in advance
[Music]
okay
we will cover benefits number five
uh
[Music]
eligible covered expenses include a few
months you know covering expenses
expenses to receive emergency medical
attention
society
[Music]
is
so maximum demand seven hundred dollars
okay
expenses for ambulance transportation
ambulance
and ground ambulance okay
expenses for emergency dental treatment
[Music]
doctor
up to 3000
to have your body prepared where you die
and the course of the standard
transportation container normally used
by the airlines
or up to three thousand
uh to have your body prepared
in the cost of a standard burial
container
okay
or up to three thousand pounds
[Music]
physician recommends that you return
your home because of your emergency
it would be better if you just go back
to the philippines because the cost of
the operation would cost this much this
much as much
[Music]
dollars
um
and they will pay for the economy class
airfare
stretcher airfare etc etc
[Music]
uh extra expenses for meals hotels uh
phone calls and taxi
[Music]
uh they will cover the airfare dinpo
okay expenses for child care
expenses to return children under your
care so
filipinas
okay
again
complete details
[Music]
yeah if you are hospitalized for more
than 72 hours when three days hospital
we will reimburse up to 100 dollars for
each 24-hour period to a maximum of 300.
[Music]
television
hospital
[Music]
our assistance center again paulo
against assistance center
you may return home
pedigree filipinas without terminating
your coverage poor but then mr
suspendant but will not terminate after
you leave canada
so maria in state or
they can restart again
planning
insurance coverage
there will be no refund of premium for
any of the days during your return home
because
what is not covered under medical uh
emergency medical insurance
[Music]
go over any sickness that manifests
during the waiting period
effectively
[Music]
oh
if in the 180 days before the effective
date you require any form of
nitroglycerin
either
or you spray for the relief of angina
[Music]
now
or passengers now
made of pre-existing condition
okay
that is not stable
a pre-existing condition that is not
stable in the 180 days
so
[Music]
number four
expenses for a pre-existing conditions
for which you were hospitalized either
more than once
or for at least two consecutive days in
the 12-month period before your
effective date of insurance
explanation
consecutive days
are in a hospital
height
either more than once i mean
um
so more than once hospital
within one year
so january
1st 2022 alistar pero
january
1st
hospital
and
[Music]
covered expenses that exceed the maximum
insured amount available
insurance coverage
[Music]
hospitalization
to be honest with you
at least
50 000.
canada
passage
[Music]
mo for more than let's say 20 days about
25 days
at least
[Music]
foreign
so any expenses or benefits
if the information provided on
the application for insurance is not
truthful
expenses
number eight covered expenses that
exceed eighty percent of those we would
normally pay
um
tomorrow's assistance center
any treatment that is not for emergency
containment emergency dubai continued
treatment of a medical condition when
you have already received emergency
treatment for that condition during your
trip if our medical advisors determine
that the medical emergency has ended
[Music]
let's say
inflicted
[Music]
okay
or your pregnancy or childbirth or
complications
okay
[Music]
sorry it's already 50 minutes better
this is for your own good so
uh
proof of travel dates etc copy of your
ticket etc what is your
uh tournament what is covered under
travel accident insurance
of life limbo sight
we will pay up to the maximum according
to the following schedule for loss of
limb uh
life or sight
fifty thousand or up to fifty thousand
kuna balance
arms or legs
after twenty five thousand one eyeland
one limb or uh
[Music]
not following a recommended or
prescribed therapy necessary agreement
uh intoxication medications are drugs
alcohol or evangel okay
minor mental or emotional disorder
criminal act
of terrorism
okay
at least this is better i think than
reading by yourself
[Music]
okay
uh if you are making a claim under
travel
accident insurance if your body is not
found within 12 months ago
within 12 months in the kamakita they
will presume you dead
okay
if a claim is made under this insurance
we will need police autopsy coroner's
report medical records death certificate
as applicable
we're going to the optional trip
interruption insurance you can just read
on this okay so
[Music]
oh
this is not as uh
as difficult to understand as the
emergency coverage book or medical code
range
okay what is not covered under uh
optional trip interruption medical
condition
uh related to a covered defense yeah
an event which at the effective date of
this insurance you or your travel
companion knew
or it was reasonable to expect may
eventually prevent you from completing
your trip so yeah
okay
and then yeah
12. i don't want to take up more of your
time it's 53 minutes already
[Music]
in the video
but but just read this uh and then if
you have any questions you can contact
me or alexis or
young assistant center
must be listening from midnight or in
the game
alexis because we're busy
uh you can always call the assistant
center 24 hours a day
okay
if you're making a claim at the trip
interruption
assistance center
and that's the
the
uh the word of the day assistance and
there geraldine should be proof of the
cause of the claim
approved so complete original and used
transportation
original passenger receipt original
receipt for the travel arrangements
[Music]
etc
any of the other invoice or receipt
supporting the claim
okay
almost done guys thanks for your time
um
[Music]
okay
we're done actually what else do you
need to know
on this part now okay your policy is
issued on the basis of information
provided in your application
in the during the application
you know
[Music]
was only based on your
answers
the insurance is not is uh this
insurance is void
in the case of fraud or attempted fraud
and i know attempted fraud foreign
[Music]
despite any other provisions in this
contract this contract is subject to the
statutory conditions contained in the
governing provincial statute so
depending on
then
okay
so yeah
upon payment of premium this document
becomes a binding contract
okay
so
application medical questionnaire etc
so yeah
to whom will we pay you or the your
benefits if you have a claim
from
uh so except in the case of your death
you will pay the expenses covered under
this insurance to you
pero in the case of death that the
leniency estate order
or
10 yen
and then page 11
we're going to discuss guys it's a 57
minutes already
definition of terms
of terrorism act of war activities of
daily living
and age etcetera expiry date emergency
or just paid out your own copy
immediate family
medical
condition medical
[Music]
notice on privacy your privacy matters
just write this down somewhere or repeat
this policy
this is not the policy i mean this is
the
like the uh
policies
[Music]
okay this is the policy in general okay
so again
sorry
i'm a toy collector obviously as you can
see so again guys uh thank you for the
time and again this is robin tolentino
i'm the husband of marie alexis
torrentino your travel
manager international travel manager uh
we've been married for
um well since 2009
and i've been in the insurance industry
for more than five years
i'm also an rn in the red regional
hospital
and as i've said i'm an insured licensed
and investment
advisor for more than five years so if
you have any needs insurance for
as you can see i'm very thorough and
very
detailed
i'm very detailed
you can call
me alexis you can contact alexis and let
her know that you want to book an
appointment with me
and i can show you the different kinds
of insurance in canada
from one
insurance because
based on experience there are uh some
companies here in uh san clasi
langladian you know offering insurance
so it's either term insurance loan or
whole life insurance plan or universal
life insurance now
poho and i'll explain everything to you
as
far as i can because that's my principle
in life although i'm registered you know
it's not important
[Music]
to provide them information on how to
protect their
life and
protect their monetary value as a person
expenses
[Music]
uh thank you for watching this video and
i hope to hear from you guys i hope to
hear from you honestly
if you are anywhere from anywhere within
alberta let me know
i can meet you up or we can do a zoom
meeting
uh i can give you a really really good
uh financial plan because as i said i
only don't i i just don't
do
insurance
plans but i also do
investment plans so
iesp's tfsas
i'll explain them in detail kapaga like
meeting professors
one hour and 20 seconds and running
again thank you guys for the time and i
hope to hear from you thanks for getting
a travel insurance from us from me and
alexis and thank you for trusting alexis
in um
in her business travel business she's
been around for more than
i mean she's been in the travel business
for
more than me 12 or 15 years i'd say in
the philippines and here in canada
she's really good she's an expert
to be honest with you
so again thank you for your trust and
thank you for your time
let me know if you have questions um
yeah robin you can search me up on
facebook with robin tolentino or just
ask alexis my wife and then we can talk
and um yeah it's either you
i can help you become
an agent yourself if you want to be an
agent or
uh if you have any questions or if you
want to
if you intend to
get your family or yourself life
insurance coverage or investments okay
again thank you guys sorry if i if that
[Music]
thank you guys so much and i hope to
hear from you
and take care stay safe god bless
everyone all right
bye thank you very much
[Music]